[Music]
hello friends
welcome back to our channel
i am your tosca instructor and my name
is kumaresh
i have total 14 years of it experience
in software development and test
automation thank you for connecting with
us
hope you are doing well
let's start our today's session
through this video i will explain the
detailed overview and implementation
approaches of tosca test case design
the explanation will be done through
hands-on demonstration at the previously
developed test case
tosca test case design is an approach to
isolate the test data from the technical
sections of test cases
so the data and test cases are kept
separately
in short it is also known as tcd
the tosca test case design section has
the capability to break our test cases
into a logical structure
it is also help us to plan and design
the test cases in an efficient and
structured way to reduce the development
and maintenance efforts
the primary activities of tcd are
create the test sheets which is a
combination of all possible test cases
for any particular scenario or template
basically test sheets are holding the
data for different combinations
the concept of class in test case design
approach helps to reuse the common data
across the test cases which reduce the
efforts of data management
[Music]
with the help of instances we can create
the specific data for test sheets tcd
attributes or tcd classes
create test case templates and assign
the test sheets
we need to instantiate or reinstantiate
templates to generate the instance test
cases as per the test sheets
it manages test data in test sheets and
execute the instance test cases
before starting of tcd implementation we
need to familiar with some tcd objects
which are mostly used in tcd
i am explaining them one by one
folder
the test case design folder is used to
group the test sheets or classes in a
logical way
test sheet is a list of data for all
possible combinations of toska test
cases
each data set represents one unique test
case
attribute
is referred to as the different data
parameters corresponding to each
application field
attribute which are not business
relevant
are used for comment or description
purposes
the result attribute
is used for result purposes
instances collection
holds the instances i.e all possible
values available for particular
attribute
instances
is the value of each attribute slash
parameter
it can be created test sheets attributes
or class level
instances of test sheets are basically a
test case name
class
is similar to test sheets but it's used
for the reusable purpose
all the common data are stored here
which can be reused in multiple test
sheets
class reference
is acting as a link of classes from test
sheets
we can create it with the drag drop
method
the object hierarchies in test case
design are
a test sheet may have attributes
instances test steps and class
references
a class may be the combinations of class
attributes and instances
again an attribute can keeps further
a step can keeps more steps and
attributes
advantages of tcd approach are
[Music]
handling of dynamic test data and
objects are very easy
it helps to reuse of data in different
test cases
no scripting is required to implement
tcd
data and technical components are kept
separately
in the case of data change no need to
modify the test cases
[Music]
the main disadvantages of tcd is that
the test case design section are
thus approach is very complicated and
little expensive
also the ui takes time to understand all
right let's start the demonstration on
test case design
i will guide you the step-by-step
approaches to implement tcd in an
existing test case
first we need to create the test data
sheet in test case design section
we will implement tcd in this test case
which was developed previously
now we open the test case design section
as a floating window on top of test case
section
[Music]
check out the tcd section
to create the data sheet we need to
right click on the tcd folder
we rename it to data set 1.
now we will create the attribute of the
datasheet as the test data parameter
such as url
after that we need to create the
instances of url attribute which will be
treated as test data
we are adding two urls for google as
values
[Music]
similarly we will add another attribute
as search value which will represent the
data parameter to store values of google
search text
and created two instances as test data
[Music]
next we need to create the instances of
datasheet
this instances will be represented as
the test case name later
here we create two instances test case
underscore 0 1 and test case underscore
0 2.
after creation of data sheet instances
we need to assign assign attribute
values for each of the instances
we can do it from details section
we will select the values from attribute
drop down
for two instances we will select
different set of data which are defined
during attribute creation
the test data sheet is now created
successfully
[Music]
now i will demonstrate the approach to
create a template test case and assign
the data sheet
first go to the corresponding test case
and perform checkout operation to make
it editable
right click on the test case and select
the option convert to template to make
to as template test case
[Music]
now drag the data sheet data set 1 and
drop it to the template test case
[Music]
after the data sheet assignment
same can be viewed from the property
section against the property name as
schema path
now we will assign or replace the data
parameter in the template test case by
dragging the attribute from the test
data sheet into the value field of the
test case
instead of drag drop method we can
directly type the syntax in the value
field
we will replace all the hard coded value
from the test case
the datasheet assignment is now
completed
next we will generate the instance test
cases by right clicking on the template
test case and selecting the create
template instance option
after confirming the process it will
take few seconds to generate the
instance test cases with the data
defined in tcd
here two test cases will be created as
per the definition in the datasheet
instances
we can also see that the data will be
updated as per the data provided in our
data set 1 data sheet
the implementation test case design is
now completed
we will now execute the instance test
case from execution list to ensure the
correctness of the implementation
dock or close the test case design
section and go to execution section
create a new execution list with name
tcd
we can assign any name here
now we need to drag and drop the newly
generated instance test cases here
we can execute entire execution list
but to save time we are selecting first
test case and run it
the automated script will perform the
defined test steps including google
search
[Music]
opening the trisendis official portal
from the search result displayed in the
google page and validate the trisendis
logo
[Music]
after completion of execution the
execution logs will be available in the
execution list which contains the logs
for each of the steps including
verifications
the implementation test case design is
now completed
i will show how to create class in tcd
to reuse data in multiple data sheets
first navigate to test case design
section
to create class right click on any
desire folder and then click on create
class option available in menu with icon
c
we can rename it
we will now follow the same approach to
create the class instances and the
attributes which was used during data
sheet creation
here we will create two class instances
set 1 and set 2.
also we will create one attribute as
data parameter which represents the url
two instances as the value of this
attribute will be created
[Music]
now we need to assign assign attribute
values for each of the instances of the
class
it can be done from the details section
by selecting the value from attributes
drop down
we will now assign this class to
datasheet by drag and drop it to
datasheet
now we will select the corresponding
instance which represents the data set
from the class reference by selecting
this the corresponding url will be
assigned to the test data sheet
the same class can be assigned to
multiple data sheets to reuse the data
we can now assign this attributes of
class reference to the template test
case as the data sheet attributes thanks
for watching this video
that's all about tosca test case design
[Music]
we will learn more about tosca features
in next video
please visit our website lambdageeks.com
for more articles on technology
engineering mathematics and various
other domain
you can check our other website as well
[Music]
we have features like youtube trends
twitter trends
scientific calculator and many more
other tools
if you like our video please like
comment and share
if you have any questions please comment
and we will resolve your query